Appreciate y'all being here.
We're going to jump right into questions
and then after the press conference,
we'll make sure everyone gets photo
opportunities. So, we'll start with
Aaron.
Keelan, when you think about your first
day here, what's it like just to be in
the building and uh kind of have it soak
up the moment and have a follow-up for
DeMeco. Thank you.
Uh yeah, I mean that's first off a
blessing. Obviously, you uh you dream of
this your whole life.
Just getting an opportunity to play in
the NFL. Um that's a lifelong dream. So,
you get that opportunity. I'm so
grateful that it's, you know, the
Houston Texans and I get to come in here
and meet all these wonderful people that
I've met and uh it's a great it's a
great place. You can tell the people are
genuine and I'm just so excited to get
to work.
For DeMeco, you think about we're
watching the video and you're talking
about this is the kind of player we
need. You want toughness on offense. I
just see if you could expand on that a
little bit. Thank you.
Yeah, we're we're excited, you know, for
Keelan to be a part of our team, right?
Because he represents, you know, what
we're about and that's about playing
tough, playing physical. It's about
finishing and for anyone that's watched
this young man's tape, you know, the
highlight of his tape is how he finishes
plays. It's something that's innate,
something that's in him and something
that we truly believe in here. And I
know he's going to bring that toughness
and that physicality and that finish
mindset, that relentless mindset that we
look for. He's bringing that to our
team. So, that's why we're fired up to
have him.
This is for Nick and I guess maybe
DeMeco a little bit. Nick, last night
you mentioned some of the elements of
the grade that you had on Keelan that
were, you know, were really high. Can
you kind of reveal without revealing too
much about those elements specifically?
Yeah, anytime you're creating a profile
on a player, there's obviously the
physical components on the field and
then you look at some of the intangible
items that are going to apply to the
player from a coachability, from an
intelligence standpoint, football
character,
instincts, toughness, overall
competitiveness, the way DeMeco alluded
to it. So, those are things like we
prioritize in this program. We
prioritize and every player is evaluated
based on that criteria. And Keelan like
stood head and shoulders above a lot of
other players. So, that's a part of the
evaluation. So, when you combine that
with what you see on the tape, then you
put the profile of the player together
and say like this is what a Houston
Texans football player looks like. So,
we take a lot of pride and we put a lot
of value in that. Like you guys have
been around our team like and we've
talked about this. You win with people
and you win with mental and physical
toughness. That's what this league is
about. So, in order to be physical, in
order to play with mental physical
toughness, you have to add players to
your team that possess those qualities.
So, if you say that's what you're about,
well, then it's our responsibility to go
out there and find it and like nobody
epitomizes more than more than Keelan,
which is why he's sitting in a chair
next to us.
Keelan, um you were speaking yesterday
about Right here. Jonathan Alexander,
Houston Chronicle. Nice to meet you.
Uh you were speaking yesterday about uh
kind of your mindset. Um other people
have described you as kind of like
playing with like a nasty mindset. Um
like you finish people. But, I'm just
curious how you adopted that. Where that
came from, what what influences that? Is
it Is it your upbringing, where you came
from? What influences that?
I mean, I think you can point to a lot
of a of areas. I think I'm just first
and foremost, I'm a competitor. I just
love to compete in everything I do and I
think if you're a true competitor, you
want to finish it like as an offensive
lineman, you want to put the dude in the
dirt. I mean, you want to play it that
way till the whistle. Um you want to
compete at a high level um and you want
to be the best about it. So, I think
that's just, you know, just the
competitor in me. I've always had that
fire about me. So, I think that's where
it comes from.
Uh this is for Nick and DeMeco.
Obviously, whenever a player gets
picked, there's always talk, "Well, this
team wanted him before, so you had to go
up and get him." How do you prepare for
that? Like maybe leading up to it where
you talk about acting stuff up and then
in the moment and how hectic can it be
when you want a guy and you anticipate
that maybe team in front of you would
want the same guy. Yeah, it's really
about organization and preparation and
then capitalizing the opportunity when
it presents itself. So, I mean, DeMeco
and I talk, I would say, I mean, 40
times a day. So, we're talking about
players, we're talking about different
scenarios. He probably wants me out of
his office plenty of the time. But,
you're always going through different
scenarios. And in our situation, say
once we got into like 16, 17, 18, 19,
20, you start to look at, "All right,
who are the players that are available?
Who are some of the players that we
would consider taking?" And you kind of
create some buckets. And then as you go
through, again, we don't really know
what other teams are going to do. Like
you try to as best you can make an
estimation and look at the the roster,
"Hey, there's some players that they
might be interested in." It doesn't mean
that for sure they're going to be you're
going to be interested in the same
player. And then we look at it through
the lens of in the end, what's the best
thing for the Houston Texans? We can't
worry about what other teams are doing.
They're going to make their decisions.
We have to make our decisions
independent of what anybody else is
doing. So, in terms of how chaotic it
it's really not. It's pretty fluid. It's
ongoing. And we just kind of react and
we're ready to go. And if you do a
trade, you make a trade and you pick the
player. If you can't consummate the
trade, then you prepare for the next
opportunity in front of you. So, we're
pretty consistent. It'll be no different
here tonight when we get started here in
a few hours. Kenyon,
have you had a chance to I know you
haven't been in town long, but have you
had a chance to meet any other members
of the offense since you landed in
Houston? Uh yes, sir. Uh C.J. Stroud uh
came by, text me. Will text me. Um and
C.J. Stroud came by the hotel. We talked
for a long time. Um he's a great human
being first and foremost, but obviously,
we all know how he how he is out there
on the grass and he's
he's made of the right stuff. So, he's a
he's a great dude, man. Uh just great
for him to come up there and take the
time to come talk to me.
Uh Kenyon, right in here. Uh earlier
today, it was said by by Coach Keeton
that you met with Cole Popovich before
the draft. Um what were those
conversations like and what did you
think about the overall offensive
approach that he was kind of talking
with you about? Yeah, I mean, I I really
loved my time with Coach Pop. Um he put
me through a lot of things that, you
know, he's looking for and, you know, in
terms of how he's going to throw hands,
all them all them details kind of thing
and, you know, different than what I did
in college, but, you know, I just soaked
it in. Just try to take the coaching. Um
he's he's there to coach me and uh see
what I had, see how I was moving and I I
really enjoyed the time and the Zoom I
had with him. I'm just talking ball and
I loved it.
Uh DeMeco, um when you were looking at
Kenyon's film and and and you were
obviously liking what you were seeing,
what what what
what did you and and Nick and Kenyon
envision for him?
Uh for me, when I'm I'm watching the
film of all these offensive linemen,
right? Studying a lot of different guys
and when I put on his tape, I typed in
the word swarm.
And that's what it that's what I saw on
tape. That's the type of player that I
saw and the envision is he can he play
multiple spots on the interior part of
the offensive line. Though he spent a
lot of time at right guard. He snapped
the ball at Senior Bowl, did a really
good job of that. Smart young man,
bright young man. We're just happy to
work with him. See may the best five
guys go out there and help us win some
games. He's ready to compete. He's
talked about how he loves to compete.
That's how he gained his edge and that's
what we're all about. I saw that
competitor mindset. I saw it jump off of
the tape and that made it an easy
choice. And for us and for me, we're
drafting, you see a guy you want. That's
why I love working with Nick. We see a
guy we want. We see a guy who fits our
building, fits what we're about, fits
our culture. Let's go get the guy, add
him to our team.
Uh this is for DeMeco and Nick. When
when y'all um hired Popovich as the
offensive um line coach, what what was
it that y'all liked about Cole Popovich
and is
is this is it safe to say that the what
we've seen with this offensive line is
kind of
a significant impact of his with with
the with the turnover and everything? Go
ahead, Nick. Yeah, me hiring Cole, the
one thing in the interviewing process,
like Cole is a a brilliant coach. He's a
very smart guy and he's not just
offensive line driven. Like he's very
thoughtful in seeing the entire picture
of the offensive line, right? And how it
all fits together. He's very thoughtful
in making sure, "Hey, which guys do I
need? What do they do well?" And he he
does a really good job. If you guys ever
get a opportunity to see him work in his
individuals and how he takes the time to
coach the guys up on all the fine, small
details that's really important for an
offensive lineman. And it's him being
detailed, being thorough as a coach and
never
stuck on what he's always done. He's
always trying to help his players,
always trying to improve his players.
And to me, that's the signs of a really
good coach. He's a excellent
communicator, does a really great job on
game day as well. We need to make
adjustments. Cole is the guy who sees
it, can make the adjustments and get us
in the right right situation. So, he's
all the things you want in a coach.
Nick and I guess to an extent, DeMeco,
how much of what happens on
changes what you would maybe expect to
do on day two? I know you guys moved
back about 20 spots in the third round,
but also, you know, now you have Kenyon,
offensive lineman. Would you, you know,
still be expected to maybe draft an
offensive lineman as well? How much
changes from after things are done in
the first round to the second round?
Always open for business on anything.
Doesn't necessarily take us just because
you select one player doesn't
necessarily take you out of either a
player or a position. Like we'll go back
to what we've kind of done today is look
at the board and said, "All right, here
are certain players graded to a certain
level. What are our opportunities? We're
scheduled to pick right now at 38 with
five or six picks in.
What are options? Who are the players
that we've identified? If they're
available, we pick them, great. If not,
we move back. And then we're scheduled
to pick at 59 and then 91 or whatever it
is right now. So, we'll just follow the
board, look at our grades. In the end,
we always go back to our grades. What do
we say about the player? What have our
scouts said? What have the coaches said?
And then just kind of work ourselves
around the board and try to make good
smart decisions. I mean, we didn't go
into the draft last year anticipating we
were going to draft draft Jaylon
Johnson, but that's the way the board
fell. So, we took both players. So, if
there's an opportunity to draft another
offensive lineman that makes sense,
we'll certainly consider it. We're not
going to rule it out because you really
never know when you're going to need
these players and what the overall
constitution of the team is going to
look like. I mean, we can't sit here
today and say, "Well, we know what it's
going to look like in September." It
could change. So, we're always planning
for what's in front of us, but we're
going to add good players with the right
mentality, with the right mindset. Let
the players ultimately sort itself out
and then if we got to make some
decisions at some point, then we'll make
decisions we feel are best for the team.
Kenyon, Brent Key today was telling me
that there was a conditioning test and
guys were, you know, trying to get
through it. It was a tough one. You were
literally pushing your teammates and
yelling. Do you remember that? Was that
this year or last year? Just what can
you tell me about that? And I have a
follow-up.
Uh yes, sir. I mean, I definitely
remember that, but it was just who I am
every day. Uh no different conditioning
test. First day,
um winter jacket drills, inside run.
It's just, "Hey, you competitor. You
want all your teammates to be wired the
same way you are and uh get after it."
So, you're going to push some guys to
their limit and you hope that they push
you to your limit. Iron sharpens iron.
So, you still watch even though after
you were done, you were watching the
tape and critiquing the practice stuff.
He said that you were kind of going back
and wondering, you know, was the
standard, you know, still going the way
you wanted it to with your younger
teammates? Yeah, I mean, there's a lot
of new new faces in there on the O-line
over there at Georgia Tech. So, you want
to watch the tape. You know, I'm going
into practice. Don't know a lot of the
guys. So, a lot of new faces over there.
So, I just want to see what they're
about, see how they play the game. And
obviously, when you go to practice, I'm
going to hey, if I see something on
tape, I'm going to let them know like,
"Hey, I think this, yada yada." So, you
just you want them to I would love to be
a sponge and you want them to just soak
it up. Lastly, uh
he called you an underrated athlete and
they were saying that you ran in the
4.9s. You were actually disappointed to
run like I think it was 5.05 at the at
the combine.
And you basketball, that stuff. What is
your background in those sports and
other thing kind of say about you as an
athlete? Thank you.
Uh yes, sir. I mean, I think I'm a good
athlete, obviously. You know, I don't
want to toot my own horn, but I think I
move well. Um grew up didn't play
offensive line till I got to college.
So, grew up playing tight end and
D-line. Um played all sorts of sports,
played basketball, threw shot put. So,
you know,
jack of all trades kind of deal.
Kenyon, I wanted to ask you a little bit
more about um what you were saying
earlier when C.J. came by. Um did y'all
break bread? What did you make of him
coming over to the hotel and and and
what can you tell us about, I guess, the
general message?
Yeah, I mean, I think first of all, he
was just excited. Um
you know, you could tell he's a leader.
He's made like I said, he's made of the
right stuff. So, he just wanted to come
over there and just, hey, congratulate
me. Um just, you know, welcome me and uh
just, I mean, just talking life, you
know? Nothing special. Uh just guys
being guys, just talking ball and
wishing me luck. And he said, "Hey, if
you need anything, I'm here for you."
So, what you want your quarterback.
Kenyon, you were a player that entered
the transfer portal and went to Georgia
Tech and you mentioned that you didn't
play offensive line till you got to
college. Can you talk about your
relationship with Brent Key and what he
meant to be able to help you get to
where you are today.
Yeah, I mean Brent Key's a great ball
coach, great man, just what he stood for
at Georgia Tech. Um the way he ran the
program, I think, you know, that's the
way it should be ran. It was built on
toughness. It was just built on how we
were going to be committed, how we were
going work with your teammates. It was
it was ran the right way and obviously
he's a O-line guy, so he's always
getting his nose in the offensive line
and he and you know, he just developed
me in the right way. He'd always bring
me in his office, talk life first and
foremost and then he'd be like, "Hey,
fix this, fix this." So, he he's a
really good ball coach and he's, you
know, I can credit him for for where I'm
sitting today.
Pedro Hernandez for Televisa.
Keilan, with Houston Texans being so
close to Mexico, there's a huge fan base
over there in Mexico and Monterrey. Any
message to more of our international
fans outside of Houston?
Heck yeah, I mean, love all my fans.
Let's get let's get after it this year.
Um let's play some football and uh let's
just let's swarm. Let's go let's go win
some games.
All right.
All right, thank you guys. We're going
to take a quick Thanks.